Guide to the John G. Magee Family Papers
Magee Family (John G.) Papers
- Photographs and Films, 1870 1965; Series VI
  - Films and videos
    - Films made by John Magee
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 2, no date (Box 22)
        Students on University of Nanking campus; group with Red Cross armbands; groups of children walking downn street, with older woman missionary "Deaconess Henderson" (probably Maud Truxton Henderson)
        Digital file available.
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 3, 1927 1928 (Box 22)
        Consecration of Bishop Ding, Assistant Bishop of Fujian (Fukien), in Shanghai, November 1927, showing theological students and professors and Episcopal missionaries; General Synod of 1928, scenes at St. John's University
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 4, 1927 1927 (Box 22)
        Kindergarten and church in Maebashi, Japan; Japanese individuals and missionaries; street scenes
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 5, 1927 1927 (Box 22)
        "Easter Services at St. John's University, Shanghai in 1927 when all missionaries had been withdrawn from the interior by foreign Consuls"; "Clergy and others coming from meeting in interest of evangelistic work, November, 1927"; "Conference on Educational Work, St. John's University, November 1927"
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 6, 1928 1932 (Box 22)
        Flood in Nanjing, September 1931; scenes in Hsiakwan district; "Graduation exercises for Short Term School for teaching women...Nanking, May 1931"; Construction at St. Paul's Church, Nanking; "Scenes in Yangchow, 1928..."; "Funeral of Commissioner of Posts, Hsiakwan, July, 1930..." (elaborate funeral procession);"Chapei, the part of Shanghai destroyed in fighting between Chinese and Japanese, February 1932" (destruction of city, Japanese soldiers)
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 7, no date (Box 22)
        Color film showing unidentified ceremony, apparently in temple; scenes of Western individuals, including baby; scenes in tropical area, of workers, "Grand Hotel Recreation Club" (Taiwan?)
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 8, 1930 1939 (Box 22)
        Scenes in Kusatu, Japan, including "sulphur baths"; Japanese children playing games; missionary Miss Cornwall-Legh and Japanese clergy
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 9, 1937 1938 (Box 23)
        Scenes related to Nanking Massacre - victims being carried to dispensary, treatment of wounds, activities in refugee camp with straw huts, destroyed areas of Nanjing; individuals at International Relief headquarters looking at piles of petitions for help; group of individuals holding silk banners.Notes explaining scenes in the film are available in Box 6, Folders 29-30.
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 10, 1928 1932 (Box 23)
        Scenes from period when roads in Nanjing were rebuilt prior to state funeral of Sun Yat-sen; 20,000-40,000 houses in the path of new roads were destroyed or desconstructed by their owners; Sun Yat-sen funeral procession, May 1928; construction of new gate to city, 1931; fire near mission compound; construction on new building for women's work, 1932
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 11, 1928 1931 (Box 23)
        "Christmas service at Church of the Triumphant Way, Hsiakwan, Nanking" and festivities following; Chinese clergy and their families; "Sports Day at Tao Sheng School, 1930";"Annual Easter Service at Church Cemetery near Nanking, 1929"; "Neighborhood children play in mission grounds... 1928 and 1929"; "Morning chapel, Tao Sheng School... Bishop Graves' visit for confirmation, 1931"
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 -Reel 12, 1930 1939 (Box 23)
        "Kusatsu, the Famous Hot Sulphur Springs of Japan..."; Church, dispensary, home of missionary Miss Cornwall-Legh, leper village and leprosy patients, children playing, "church band" that plays music in streets with deacon preaching to non-Christians
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 13, 1928 (Box 23)
        Scenes at University of Nanking in 1928 following takeover of Nankjing by Chinese Nationalist troops; destruction of faculty residences; Miss Moffett, Treasurer of Presbyterian Mission in Nanking who was wounded by soldiers; Presbyterian and Quaker Mission buildings damaged by soldiers, St. Paul's Church occupied by Kuomingtang as their political headquarters
      - Magee China footage (7 small 16 mm reels, 1 DVD), 1929 1938 (Box OV1)
        Films received from Linda Granfield, 2018.
      - Magee home movies (1 VHS tape, 2 DVDs), 1920 1949 (Box OV1)
      - Copy of Library of Congress Magee footage (DVD) (Box OV1)
    - Collected films and videos
      - David B. Magee Interview (2 VHS tapes, 2 DVDs), n.d. (Box OV1)
      - "Very brief shot of Dad taking pictures in China," (VHS tape, DVD), n.d. (Box OV1)
      - "In the Name of the Emperor", Directed by Christine Choy and Nancy Tong, (VHS tape, DVD), 1995 (Box OV1)
      - "Japanese War Crimes Trials: Murder Under the Sun" (VHS tape), 1996 (Box OV1)
      - "Iris Chang on Good Morning America" (VHS tape), n.d. (Box OV1)
      - Unidentified Chinese language video (VHS tape) (Box OV1)